<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Latest News | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/</link><atom:link href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Latest News</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://mit-eesg.github.io/media/logo_hub9827e0fc18583cc83ab0e07fe3389bc_14069_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Latest News</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/</link></image><item><title>EESG power systems books now available for access</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2022-06-02-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2022-06-02-books/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several books published from our group&amp;rsquo;s work have been uploaded to our group
website. They can be accessed and downloaded under
&lt;a href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/reference_books">Resources &amp;raquo; Books&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preparing global online learners for the clean energy transition</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2022-01-31-marija-edx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2022-01-31-marija-edx/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a career devoted to making the electric power system more efficient and resilient, Marija Ilic came to MIT in 2018 eager not just to extend her research in new directions, but to prepare a new generation for the challenges of the clean-energy transition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To that end, Ilic, a senior research scientist in MIT’s Laboratory for Information and Decisions Systems (LIDS) and a senior staff member at Lincoln Laboratory in the Energy Systems Group, designed an MITx course, delivered through edX, that captures her methods and vision: &lt;a href="https://www.edx.org/course/principles-of-modeling-simulations-and-control-for-electric-energy-systems" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Principles of Modeling, Simulation, and Control for Electric Energy Systems&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course starts with fundamental concepts in electric power systems operations and management, and it steadily adds layers of complexity, posing real-world problems along the way. Ilic explains how voltage travels from point to point across transmission lines and how grid managers modulate systems to ensure that enough, but not too much, electricity flows. “To deliver power from one location to the next one, operators must constantly make adjustments to ensure that the receiving end can handle the voltage transmitted, optimizing voltage to avoid overheating the wires,” she says.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the end of the course, approximatelly 2000 enrolled students, were invited to pursue independent research projects. Some have modeled the impact of a new energy source on a local grid or for example investigated different options for reducing energy loss in transmission lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/preparing-global-online-learners-clean-energy-transition-0131" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://news.mit.edu/2022/preparing-global-online-learners-clean-energy-transition-0131&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marija Ilic elected to the National Academy of Engineering (NAE)</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2021-02-11-national-academy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2021-02-11-national-academy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The National Academy of Engineering (NAE) has elected 106 new members and 23
international members, announced NAE President John L. Anderson today. This
brings the total U.S. membership to 2,355 and the number of international
members to 298.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Election to the National Academy of Engineering is among the highest
professional distinctions accorded to an engineer. Academy membership honors
those who have made outstanding contributions to “engineering research,
practice, or education, including, where appropriate, significant contributions
to the engineering literature” and to “the pioneering of new and developing
fields of technology, making major advancements in traditional fields of
engineering, or developing/implementing innovative approaches to engineering
education.” Election of new NAE members is the culmination of a yearlong
process. The ballot is set in December and the final vote for membership occurs
during January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Individuals in the newly elected class will be formally inducted during the
NAE’s annual meeting on Oct. 3, 2021. A list of the new members and
international members follows, with their primary affiliations at the time of
election and a brief statement of their principal engineering accomplishments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nae.edu/248499/National-Academy-of-Engineering-Elects-106-Members-and-23-International-Members" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.nae.edu/248499/National-Academy-of-Engineering-Elects-106-Members-and-23-International-Members&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marija Ilic receives the IEEE PES Outstanding Power Engineering Educator award</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-08-04-marija-pes-award/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-08-04-marija-pes-award/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MIT co-PIs awarded grant for ARPAE-E's PERFORM program</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-06-24-grant-perform/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-06-24-grant-perform/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shedding light on complex power systems</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-04-23-marija-mit-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2020-04-23-marija-mit-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the earliest days of streetcars and public utilities, electric power systems have had a fairly standard structure: for a given area, a few large generation plants produce and distribute electricity to customers. It is a one-directional structure, with the energy plants being the only source of power for many end users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, however, electricity can be generated from many and varied sources — and move through the system in multiple directions. An electric power system may include stands of huge turbines capturing wild ocean winds, for instance. There might be solar farms of a hundred megawatts or more, or houses with solar panels on their roofs that some days make more electricity than occupants need, some days much less. And there are electric cars, their batteries hoarding stored energy overnight. Users may draw electricity from one source or another, or feed it back into the system, all at the same time. Add to that the trend toward open electricity markets, where end users like households can pick and choose the electricity services they buy depending on their needs. How should systems operators integrate all these while keeping the grid stable and ensuring power gets to where it is needed?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To explore this question, Ilic has developed a new way to model complex power systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Electric power systems, even traditional ones, are complex and heterogeneous to begin with. They cover wide geographical areas and have legal and political barriers to contend with, such as state borders and energy policies. In addition, all electric power systems have inherent physical limitations. For instance, power does not flow in a set path in an electric grid, but rather along all possible paths connecting supply to demand. To maintain grid stability and quality of service, then, the system must control for the impact of interconnections: a change in supply and demand at one point in a system changes supply and demand for the other points in the system. This means there is much more complexity to manage as new sources of energy (more interconnections) with sometimes unpredictable supply (such as wind or solar power) come into play. Ultimately, however, to maintain stability and quality of service, and to balance supply and demand within the system, it comes down to a relatively simple concept: the power consumed and the rate at which it is consumed (plus whatever is lost along the way), must always equal the power produced and the rate at which it is produced.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marija Ilic delivers keynote talk at 2019 FREEDM Research Symposium</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prof. Marija Ilic was invited to deliver a keynote speech at the Future
Renewable Electric Energy Delivery and Management
(&lt;a href="https://www.freedm.ncsu.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FREEDM&lt;/a>) Research Symposium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her presentation titled ‘The Future of Electric Power Grid ‘ can be found &lt;a href="https://www.freedm.ncsu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Ilic-MIT-Future-of-the-Grid.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Marija and friends" srcset="
/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/featured2_hu2384312725eb45199e14e2b4c9b749c9_439360_734a006b9c980bf34828ef66e2749eb0.webp 400w,
/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/featured2_hu2384312725eb45199e14e2b4c9b749c9_439360_312849279207560439716d5021fddfee.webp 760w,
/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/featured2_hu2384312725eb45199e14e2b4c9b749c9_439360_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://mit-eesg.github.io/post/2019-05-02-marija-keynote/featured2_hu2384312725eb45199e14e2b4c9b749c9_439360_734a006b9c980bf34828ef66e2749eb0.webp"
width="570"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>