<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 spring | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/tag/2022-spring/</link><atom:link href="https://eesg.mit.edu/tag/2022-spring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>2022 spring</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://eesg.mit.edu/media/logo_hub9827e0fc18583cc83ab0e07fe3389bc_14069_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>2022 spring</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/tag/2022-spring/</link></image><item><title>Research Needs for the Clean Energy Transition</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-27-zhen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-27-zhen/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jzD-8VJy3I8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Situational Awareness and Decision Support for Enabling Power Grid Resiliency</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-20-srivistava/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-20-srivistava/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/86Zw3FG58R0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Impacts of Energy Transition on Long Term Planning of Power System: Case of Thailand</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-13-junlakarn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-13-junlakarn/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pIKsbcjKlmQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Physics-Informed Deep Reinforcement Learning for Power System Optimization and Control</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-06-zhao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-04-06-zhao/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wKfyVBbY7Ks" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Learning and Control in Power Distribution Grids</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-30-low/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-30-low/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/id5NNCwlLXs" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Electric Power System Operations and Planning in the Great Energy Systems Transition</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-23-sun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-23-sun/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MrVZ3J_Sgs0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>The Grid of Grids: Doing for Electricity What the Internet Did for Information</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-09-patterson/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-09-patterson/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tmm4jCkyquU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Over one sextillion watt hours of electricity is consumed around the world
annually - mostly produced and distributed on demand using 100-year-old
technology. There are less than 10,000 central power plants producing most of
this electricity. A primary reliance on this centralized production has left
us with increasingly troublesome issues of significant environmental impact,
transmission losses, geographic social and economic inequities, and the
increasing vulnerability of exposed and unsecured lines to natural and
man-caused disaster damage. In addition, historically, most power systems
simply feed &amp;quot;dumb&amp;quot; loads from hard wired fixed physical grids. But an
increasing focus on clean, fault tolerant, resilient, economical, and efficient
energy use is leading to us to consider transforming these systems to
significantly more interactive ones with the capability of intelligent load
management, storage, decentralized mesh wiring topologies and the employment of
an increasingly diverse set of combined clean generation sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This presentation discusses an expanded role for interconnected distributed
renewable energy microgrids in new mesh networks, based on hybrid use of AC and
DC power. It is posited that connecting power creation to power consumption in
a network of massively distributed microgrids will yield the analogous
capability of an &amp;lsquo;Enernet&amp;rsquo; or electric energy network to power fixed and mobile
loads in the 21st century. The presentation will also introduce the concept of
a transactive energy framework used to enable a combination of economic and
control techniques to manage power flows within the network to optimize
operations and commerce within a multi-tiered arrangement of both public and
private microgrids and macrogrids in a Grid-of-Grids topology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bio">Bio&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Brian T. Patterson is Chairman and co-founder of the EMerge Alliance. He is a
40 plus year veteran of the electrical and electronics industry, has an
extensive technical and work history in electronics, fiber optics and building
electrical systems technologies and holds multiple patents in those fields. He
is currently Managing Director of B. L. Coliker Associates, a market and
technology consulting firm. Prior positions include General Manager at
Armstrong World Industries, Director of AMP Incorporated’s Fiber Optic
Business, and President of an Electronic Interconnect Division of Kollmorgen
Corporation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He is the US National Council International Electrotechnical Commission’s
technical advisor to the System Evaluation Group on Low Voltage (under 1500V)
Direct Current. He is a member of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics
Engineers Standards Association, the IEEE Power and Energy Society, the
Continental Automated Buildings Association, the Power Supply Manufacturer’s
Association, and the UL/NEMA/EMerge ad hoc NFPA National Electrical Code task
group on DC power. Mr. Patterson is also past chairman of the NIST Smart Grid
Interoperability Panel Distributed Renewable Generation and Storage Distributed
Energy Work Group Microgrid Subgroup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Patterson has been a featured speaker at: US Green Building Council
International, LightFair International, American Institute of Architect,
Applied Power Electronics, International Telecommunications Energy,
International Electrotechnical Commission, International Facility Management
Association, the Smart Energy Power Association and Solar Energy Industry
Association’s Annual Solar Power International Smart Energy Week and numerous
other national and international industry, government and academic forums. He
is a professionally accredited course author and instructor for the American
Institute of Architects, the US Green Building Council, and the Illuminating
Engineering Society of North America. He has also authored articles for major
industry and professional trade magazines and is the official spokesperson of
the EMerge Alliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Safe and Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Energy Systems</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-08-baosen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-08-baosen/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gUOFTedC9Cc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Inverter-based resources such as solar and storage provide us with more
flexibility in the control of power systems. Through their power electronic
interfaces, complex control functions can be implemented to quickly respond to
changes in the system. Recently, reinforcement learning has emerged as a
popular method to find these nonlinear controllers. The key challenge with a
learning-based approach is that stability and safety constraints are difficult
to enforce on the learned controllers. In this talk, we show how model-based
control theory can be used as useful constraints on reinforcement learning,
allowing us to explicitly engineer the structure of neural network controllers
such that they guarantee system stability. The resulting controllers only use
local information and outperform conventional droop as well as strategies
learned purely by using reinforcement learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We need to talk about Low Voltage (Low Voltage Load Forecasting: Methods, Applications, and Recommendations)</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-02-haben-greetham/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-03-02-haben-greetham/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XqVVTSn7MwA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Development of the Photovoltaic (PV) Analysis and Response Support (PARS) platform</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-02-16-lu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-02-16-lu/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WI2pj8F3PGg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item><item><title>Energy &amp; Environmental Problems Facing the Third World and Their Probable Solutions</title><link>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-02-09-kothari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eesg.mit.edu/eesg_seminar/2022-02-09-kothari/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C3gwgJKDIMA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;br></description></item></channel></rss>