<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ongoing | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/ongoing/</link><atom:link href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/ongoing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ongoing</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://mit-eesg.github.io/media/logo_hub9827e0fc18583cc83ab0e07fe3389bc_14069_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>ongoing</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/ongoing/</link></image><item><title>Application of Banking Scoring and Rating for Coherent Risk Measures in Electricity Systems</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/bars-perform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/bars-perform/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is a collaboration between MIT and Lehigh University to include
fundamental risk tools from economics to balance uncertain supply and demand in
the electricity sector and improve adoption of renewable energy sources. This
critical infrastructure sector virtually affects everybody in the US, and is a
cornerstone of the efforts to make a transition to a low carbon economy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditionally, the grid relies on conventional bulk power plants to provide the
flexibility to operate power systems reliably. These assets can guarantee
available capacity except in rare events. The existing risk management strategy
protects against those rare events and aligns well with conventional
technologies. New risk management strategies are needed due to the shift in
grid resources: variable renewable resources, distributed energy resources, and
storage technologies. Management systems must be able to leverage all
capabilities of these new technologies to maintain an economical and reliable
grid. PERFORM projects aim to address that need by developing methods to
quantify and manage risk at the asset and system levels for the grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sponsor:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/technologies/projects/application-banking-scoring-and-rating-coherent-risk-measures-electricity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ARPA-E&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fundamentals of Modeling and Control for the Evolving Electric Power System Architectures (EAGER)</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/eager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/eager/</guid><description>&lt;!-- # Your project description goes here. The text will be displayed via markdown. -->
&lt;p>The main objective of this project is to formalize ground-breaking general
principles in support of investment planning and operating protocols for the
changing electric energy systems. This is crucial for assessing effects
of candidate hardware and software technologies and for creating an environment
in which flexible technologies are utilized by complementing each others'
performance and by jointly meeting societal needs. Since the performance of
many technologies of interest greatly depends on how well they are integrated
over time and stakeholders (system modules), an effective framework needs to
support decisions that are data-enabled and interactive over time and among
different system decision makers. In this project a complex dynamical systems
point of view is taken which recognizes such distributed nature of decisions
and introduces novel modeling, control and protocol principles in support of
system integration in time and space. In sharp contrast with the lack of
theoretically-provable performance in the evolving electric power system
architectures, this project explores fundamentals and takes major steps toward
solving this long-overdue problem. The most important impact will be on the way
electric power industry architectures evolve. In particular, the project will
catalyze the adoption of data-enabled decision making and automation. Notably,
this approach will help educate students to think about emerging electric
energy systems as complex dynamical systems for which much innovation is needed
and possible. Results of this research will be disseminated through a workshop
on design and control of complex energy systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Funding Agency:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2002570&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false" target="_blank" rel="noopener">National Science Foundation&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Secure Monitoring and Control of Solar PV Systems through Dynamic Watermarking</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/watermarking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/watermarking/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project will develop and demonstrate an active defense mechanism of
cyber-resilient PV distribution system operation using a dynamic watermarking
technique to monitor cybersecurity. The technique involves injecting a probe
signal onto the grid to authenticate grid actions. The approach will include
the real-time deployment of online computational algorithms in real-world
critical locations. Partners include researchers from MIT, Texas A&amp;amp;M
University, CenterPoint Energy, Argonne National Laboratory (ANL), and the
Illinois Institute of Technology (IIT). The MIT team will develop corrective
control algorithms to mitigate the negative impact of cyber attacks. The figure
below presents the topology of a test microgrid with the secondary control. The
secondary controller aims to regulate voltage magnitude and frequency at one
bus of the microgrid by tuning the setpoints of all inverters. An attacker can
compromise the microgrid by maliciously manipulating the telemetered
measurements feeding the secondary controller. If it happens, all decisions
made by the secondary controller will be wrong. To enhance the cyber resilience
of the microgrid, key questions include: 1) how to detect the cyber attacks;
and 2) how to mitigate the negative impacts of cyber attacks if the attacks are
detected. The project teams leverage a dynamic watermarking approach to detect
the cyber attacks. The MIT team are designing an observer-based approach for
taking corrective actions once attacks are detected. With the proposed
corrective controller, critical electrical variables can still be regulated in
the presence of cyber attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Funding Agency:&lt;/strong> US Department of Energy&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>