<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dymonds | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/dymonds/</link><atom:link href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/dymonds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>dymonds</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 12:52:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://mit-eesg.github.io/media/logo_hub9827e0fc18583cc83ab0e07fe3389bc_14069_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>dymonds</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/tag/dymonds/</link></image><item><title>Dynamic Monitoring and Decision Systems (DyMonDS) framework for IT-enabled engineering of retail-level energy services (RES)</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/dymonds-retail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/dymonds-retail/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this project we utilize the concept of Dynamic Monitoring and Decision
Systems (DyMoNDS) framework for IT-enabled engineering of end-to-end retail
level energy services. The main architecture of interest is a fully
integrated retail level energy service system for enhanced efficient, clean and
reliable energy services. The key role is to learn end users’ needs,
characteristics of the diverse distributed energy resources and to align their
interactions through IT-enabled protocols on-line. Moreover, the integrators
can also become a “provider of the last resource” to its end users, much the
same way as the large utility is today. They plan and invest into new
technologies for energy efficiency and quality of service to end users,
establish long-term contracts at well-defined value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sponsor:&lt;/strong> ENN Digital Energy Technology Co., Ltd., Beijing, China&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SynthEtic CloUd-based Regulation rEserve Distribution management system (SECURED)</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/secured/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/secured/</guid><description>&lt;p>The requirement of fast generation for the case when the aggregate of small
end-devices respond versus when they do not, decreases significantly. As a
result, the wear-and-tear of the fast units reduce significantly and more
importantly, the need for these expensive units can be minimized.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of the project is to utilize the flexibility offered by an aggregate
of distributed energy resources including water heaters, electric vehicles,
batteries, heating, ventilating and air-conditioning (HVAC) units. These
aggregates close to end-users are referred to as Network Optimized Distributed
Energy Resources (NODES). We utilize the notion of DyMonDS to better utilize
the end-user flexibility in light of the local uncertainties as well as the
uncertainties in price.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>