<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Premila Rowles | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/premila-rowles/</link><atom:link href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/premila-rowles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Premila Rowles</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/premila-rowles/avatar_hu61ad53ff29201d39d4c40bf72bda98d1_198923_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Premila Rowles</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/premila-rowles/</link></image><item><title>Cyber-Physical Secure Observer-Based Corrective Control under Compromised Sensor Measurements</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/paper-2022-cyber-physical-secure-corrective-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/paper-2022-cyber-physical-secure-corrective-control/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Implementation of cybersecure observers and control in microgrids; energy dynamics based approach</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/thesis-rowles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/thesis-rowles/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Secure Monitoring and Control of Solar PV Systems through Dynamic Watermarking</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/watermarking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:52:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/watermarking/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project will develop and demonstrate an active defense mechanism of
cyber-resilient PV distribution system operation using a dynamic watermarking
technique to monitor cybersecurity. The technique involves injecting a probe
signal onto the grid to authenticate grid actions. The approach will include
the real-time deployment of online computational algorithms in real-world
critical locations. Partners include researchers from MIT, Texas A&amp;amp;M
University, CenterPoint Energy, Argonne National Laboratory (ANL), and the
Illinois Institute of Technology (IIT). The MIT team will develop corrective
control algorithms to mitigate the negative impact of cyber attacks. The figure
below presents the topology of a test microgrid with the secondary control. The
secondary controller aims to regulate voltage magnitude and frequency at one
bus of the microgrid by tuning the setpoints of all inverters. An attacker can
compromise the microgrid by maliciously manipulating the telemetered
measurements feeding the secondary controller. If it happens, all decisions
made by the secondary controller will be wrong. To enhance the cyber resilience
of the microgrid, key questions include: 1) how to detect the cyber attacks;
and 2) how to mitigate the negative impacts of cyber attacks if the attacks are
detected. The project teams leverage a dynamic watermarking approach to detect
the cyber attacks. The MIT team are designing an observer-based approach for
taking corrective actions once attacks are detected. With the proposed
corrective controller, critical electrical variables can still be regulated in
the presence of cyber attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Funding Agency:&lt;/strong> US Department of Energy&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>