<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daniel Shen | Electrical Energy Systems Group</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/daniel-shen/</link><atom:link href="https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/daniel-shen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Daniel Shen</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/daniel-shen/avatar_hu6b7664f523075193f9f11d79c1c9dcfa_47988_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Daniel Shen</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/author/daniel-shen/</link></image><item><title>Valuing Uncertainties in Wind Generation: An Agent-Based Optimization Approach</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/paper-2023-valuing-uncertainties-wind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/publication/paper-2023-valuing-uncertainties-wind/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Risk-Aware Wind Bids with Distributed Optimization and Central Dispatch</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/presentation/2022-risk-aware-wind-bids/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/presentation/2022-risk-aware-wind-bids/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Application of Banking Scoring and Rating for Coherent Risk Measures in Electricity Systems</title><link>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/bars-perform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mit-eesg.github.io/project/bars-perform/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project is a collaboration between MIT and Lehigh University to include
fundamental risk tools from economics to balance uncertain supply and demand in
the electricity sector and improve adoption of renewable energy sources. This
critical infrastructure sector virtually affects everybody in the US, and is a
cornerstone of the efforts to make a transition to a low carbon economy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traditionally, the grid relies on conventional bulk power plants to provide the
flexibility to operate power systems reliably. These assets can guarantee
available capacity except in rare events. The existing risk management strategy
protects against those rare events and aligns well with conventional
technologies. New risk management strategies are needed due to the shift in
grid resources: variable renewable resources, distributed energy resources, and
storage technologies. Management systems must be able to leverage all
capabilities of these new technologies to maintain an economical and reliable
grid. PERFORM projects aim to address that need by developing methods to
quantify and manage risk at the asset and system levels for the grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sponsor:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/technologies/projects/application-banking-scoring-and-rating-coherent-risk-measures-electricity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ARPA-E&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>